## Hannah M. Lewis

Graduate Researcher

#### **CONTACT INFO**

hlewis@virginia.edu

(443) 617-1369

linkedin.com/in/hmlewis-astro/

github.com/hmlewis-astro

ORCiD: 0000-0002-7871-085X

#### **SKILLS**

# Programming Languages:

Python including pandas and scikit-learn, Jupyter notebooks, SQL, R, shell scripting

### Data Analysis:

Data science, data wrangling, data visualization including Tableau, web scraping, version control/git/GitHub, machine learning, deep learning (basic)

#### Mathematics:

Inferential and descriptive statistics, Bayesian statistics, linear algebra, calculus

#### Communication:

Scientific and technical writing and communication (for technical and nontechnical audiences)

Self-motivated learner and goal-oriented researcher, with a strong proficiency in Python, five years of experience in independent, graduate-level science research, and a genuine interest in collaborating to solve challenging data-driven problems. Seeking a position that will allow me to expand my existing data science and machine learning skillsets beyond my current area of expertise.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### StatLab Fellow

University of Virginia Library, Research Data Services 2020 - Present

- Led consultations with University researchers to find the best statistical and data analysis methods to address their unique research questions
- Developed user-friendly Jupyter notebooks for research projects involving e.g., exploratory data analysis and visualization, data wrangling, and web scraping
- Explored correlation between heat and poverty in Charlottesville, VA by combining geospatial data with US Census data
- Published data analysis tutorials on topics in coding and statistics

#### **Graduate Researcher**

University of Virginia, Department of Astronomy 2016 – Present

- Managed an array of research projects and authored multiple firstauthor works on the properties of binary stars
- Worked in a highly collaborative research group, and partnered with a wide range of researchers to produce scientific results from large datasets (>2 million observations of stars)
- Developed and provided support for well-documented, Python-based programs to guickly advance graduate-level research projects
- Collaborated with peers to develop data documentation and public user guides for large survey datasets
- Publications, press articles, and writing samples available by request

#### **TRAINING**

#### **Introduction to Machine Learning**

Self-guided via Udacity

Created and visualized a probabilistic model (using logit regression)
which predicts patient survival probability following cancer surgery,
using the Haberman Cancer Survival Dataset (github.com/hmlewisastro/haberman\_ml)

## **EDUCATION**

Ph.D. in Astronomy
Anticipated June 2021

M.S. in Astronomy 2016 – 2018

**B.A. in Physics** 2012 – 2016

University of Virginia NASA Virginia Space Grant Consortium Fellowship

University of Virginia

Jefferson Fellowship

St. Mary's College of Maryland Summa cum laude